Justin Barros

Pleasanton, California, United States



linkedin.com/in/justin-barros-51b02ba9



justiniabarros@gmail.com



510-978-9953

Summary

I have been working as a Software Engineer in Automation for 4-5 years with strong proficiency in Python and Java. I have strong skills in algorithms and a passion for both problem solving and coding. I am intermediate in JavaScript, HTML, CSS with entry level familiarity of some modern frameworks such as Django, Flask, Angular and Node.js.

My most recent role as a Core QA Software Engineer at DATERA Inc involved extensive usage of Python, Bash scripting, CI/CD (Jenkins), CRM software (Jira), Version-Control using Git and wrappers around Git. I was heavily exposed to knowledge about various stacks, data layers, OS level architectures, Cloud Storage & Cloud-related infrastructures such as clusters, storage nodes, iops, iSCSI layer, data inconsistencies, data replication, and orchestration. As part of the core QA team I often practice good quality & clean coding standards, peer code review, regressing for bugs using automated test scripts, OOP and architectural design.

For my career goals, I plan to move out of the QA field and into a more development field. If I had to choose my top picks would be either Cyber Security or Quantum Computing. However, I am interested and open to other areas such as AI/ Machine Learning/Big Data, App Development (web/mobile), and/or Stack roles (Full, Frontend, Backend). I have recently self-learned and developed in Django/DjangoRestFramework, Postgresql, Docker, and TravisCI (on GitHub). Additionally, I have recently been working on Django, Flask, MongoDB, Docker, and Pymongo, to continue expanding my skillset around the Python stack.

Experience



Software Engineer

Datera

Apr 2017 - May 2020 (3 years 2 months)

Python development for new & existing tests in order to automate and identify regressions in the product involving data read/write mismatches, race conditions from timing or asynchronous callbacks.

Python development for internal framework APIs to communicate with cluster/storage nodes.

Owned 2-3 core product features from a QA Automation standpoint.

Mentored new & existing core QA members in areas of ownership.



Junior Software Developer

Wells Fargo

Jul 2016 - Mar 2017 (9 months)

Framework development for automation testing using Java EE, Appium, Selenium, JUnit, and TestNG.

Performed QA automation testing on Android and iOS mobile devices for the Wells Fargo mobile app.

Heavy exposure to mobile development, various software architectures, QA automation/whitebox testing.



Residential Network Technician Lead/Supervisor

University of California, Santa Cruz

Nov 2015 - Jun 2016 (8 months)

- -Train and manage 20+ staff members in extensive IT computer repair, network troubleshooting, and customer relationship management
- -Produce instructional repair articles on technical computer and network repair for internal use
- -Prioritize and delegate tasks between staff to ensure increased productivity
- -Expedite the repairs of dozens of computers within the office
- -Effectively resolve hundreds of campus wide network outages
- -Successfully repair hundreds of computers with various issues ranging from virus infections, to re formats, to replacing malfunctioning hardware



Residential Network Technician

University of California, Santa Cruz

Sep 2014 - Jun 2016 (1 year 10 months)



Software Developer

Monterey Bay Marine National Sanctuary

Sep 2015 - Dec 2015 (4 months)

Back end developer for interactive dashboard to display real time utility usage from the sanctuary.

This was for a software engineering project in Computer Science: Introduction to Software Engineering (115).

Company Website:

http://montereybay.noaa.gov/vc/sec/welcome.html

Education



👸 El Cerrito High School

High School Diploma 2009 - 2012



M University of California, Santa Cruz

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

2012 - 2016

Skills

Algorithms • Python • C • Programming • Troubleshooting • Scrum • Agile Methodologies • Computer Science • Analytical Skills • Test Automation